Marie Otaki / Frontend Developer

Email - otakimarie@gmail.com **Phone** - (236) 512-4416 **Address** - Vancouver, BC. Portfoliohttps://marieotaki.comGitHubhttps://github.com/marieoog

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/marieotaki

Medium. https://marieotaki.medium.com

SUMMARY

A front-end developer who enjoys building web applications in JavaScript (React) and handson user experience (UX) design. Has over four years of experience optimizing frontend performance for web and mobile. Skilled in **HTML5**, **CSS3**, **JavaScript**, **TypeScript**, **React** and **Redux**.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Frontend Developer | Operto Guest Technologies | July 2021 - Sep 2023 |

Vancouer, Canada *Exclude May to July 2023 from the employment period.

- As the sole frontend developer, led the implementation of UI and frontend features using React and TypeScript, sharing knowledge with team members.
- Web UI renewal and mobile app implementation for high-priority projects, significantly enhancing user experiences.
- Developed UI libraries using React and Material UI, optimizing workflow through component reusability.
- Created frontend best practices documentation, enhancing team efficiency.
- Built a payment setting system connecting Salesforce and Stripe to the core system using React and Java.
- Full-stack development, including backend **Restful API** construction.
- Constantly wrote unit tests using Jest and React Testing Library so that at least 80% of the code is covered per file.

Front-end web developer | EsiHome Technologies Inc | February 2021 - July 2021 | Vanvouer, Canada

- As the primary engineer, responsible for all frontend functionalities using **React**. Shipped features such as login, attendance, report and photo gallery.
- Balanced quality and efficiency in code through detailed discussions with a designer.
- Pixel-perfect implementation of designer-created visuals using CSS.
- Designed web service architecture
- Effectively eliminated misunderstandings within the team by clearly illustrating architecture and sharing with the CTO.
- Managed tasks flexibly from planning to operation despite limited resources.

React Native Developer(Freelance / Remote) | Singan, Inc | August 2020 - September 2020 | Tokyo, Japan

- Developed a community service based on Mattermost, an OSS; targeting cancer patients under 39, focusing on frontend implementation with **React Native**.
- Coded following a comprehensive design layout in Adobe XD.
- Created forms and communicated and displayed them with the database in AWS lambda.

Front-end Developer(Contract) | COS Educational Consulting Inc. | May 2020 - September 2020 | Vancouver, Canada

- Led the planning and implementation of web pages using **HTML, CSS, JavaScript**, and **WordPress** for the owned media "HoikuPedia" based in Vancouver, Canada.
- Communicated closely with the CEO to understand the issues the company was facing and put ideas into a concrete plan.
- Analyzed the website using Google Analytics to determine what needed to be improved.
- Created a comprehensive design layout using Figma.

Full Stack Engineer(Freelance / Remote) | Greenspoon Inc. | May 2020 - July 2020 | Tokyo, Japan

- Developed an email notification system for regular subscribers of GREEN SPOON's vegetable smoothies using PHP Laravel, HTML, and CSS
- Coded according to Sketch's comprehensive layout

Web Designer | Xing Corporation | March 2018 - March 2019 | Tokyo, Japan

Web Designer | Self-Employed | May 2016 - July 2017 | Tokyo, Japan

Executive Assistant | Yahoo Japan Corporation | August 2017 - February 2018 | Tokyo, Japan

Sales Lead | Retty Inc. | May 2015 - April 2016 | Tokyo, Japan

System Administrator | NTT DATA Getronics Corporation | April 2014 - May 2015 | Tokyo, Japan

EDUCATION

Web and Mobile App Development Diploma | Cornerstone International Community College of Canada | 2019 - 2020 | Vancouver, BC

Bachelor of Literature | Kyoto Women's University | 2010 - 2014 | Kyoto, Japan